♪ In the face of turmoil ♪
♪ 面对混乱 ♪
♪ Its roots hold firmly ♪
♪ 它的根牢牢地扎根 ♪
♪ To this piece of land ♪
♪ 来到这片土地 ♪
♪ Searching for the waves ♪
♪ 寻找海浪 ♪
♪ My leaves flutter ♪
♪ 我的叶子飘动 ♪
♪ The horizon ♪
♪ 地平线 ♪
♪ Dealing from afar ♪
♪ 远方交易 ♪
♪ At the end of the world ♪
♪ 在世界的尽头 ♪
♪ It's eternity ♪
♪ 这是永恒 ♪
♪ When we meet and then part ♪
♪ 当我们相遇然后分离 ♪
♪ When we depend on each other and then move away ♪
♪ 当我们互相依赖 然后离开时 ♪
♪ I never forgot it ♪
♪ 我从未忘记 ♪
♪ By cutting the shine of swords ♪
♪ 削减剑的光芒 ♪
♪ Through the dappled sky ♪
♪ 穿过斑驳的天空 ♪
♪ Dreams that fall ♪
♪ 坠落的梦想 ♪
♪ Shatter in the wind ♪
♪ 随风破碎 ♪
♪ As the wind cuts through the waves ♪
♪ 风破浪而过 ♪
♪ Watch thousands of candles cross ♪
♪ 观看数千支蜡烛交叉 ♪
♪ The vast land and the boundless sea ♪
♪ 辽阔的土地和无边的海洋 ♪
♪ Armor and red robes flying high ♪
♪ 铠甲和红袍高飞 ♪
♪ Against bitterness, intense emotions and joyful adventures ♪
♪ 对抗苦涩、 强烈的情绪和快乐的冒险 ♪
♪ I just wish you were by my side ♪
♪ 我只希望你在我身边 ♪
♪ Make the most of what life has to offer ♪
♪ 充分利用生活所提供的一切 ♪
♪ Like tall trees with interconnected roots, I will accompany you to the ends ♪
♪ 就像根相连的大树一样 ，我会陪你走到尽头 ♪
♪ Watching the fireflies land on our shoulders ♪
♪ 看着萤火虫落在 我们的肩上 ♪
♪ Don't regret it, there are no doubts in this world ♪
♪ 不要后悔，这世界上没有疑虑 ♪
= Wonders of love =
=爱的奇迹=
= Episode 7 =
= 第 7 集 =
- Lieutenant. - What is the situation?
- 中尉。 - 现在是什么状况？
The Bingzhou garrison is about to collapse.
并州守军 即将崩溃。
Some soldiers left the city and escaped to Jianzhou.
部分士兵出城 逃往建州。
The rest have mostly given up.
其余的大部分都放弃了。
Now we count the prisoners, food supplies, stamps, letters
现在我们清点囚犯、 食品供应、邮票、信件
and many other urgent things.
以及许多其他紧急的事情。
Did you touch Han Li?
你碰过韩立吗？
When Han Li saw the situation,
韩立见状，
He escaped with the help of his personal guards.
他在私人警卫的帮助下逃脱了。
But I have sent our men to look for him.
但我已经派人 去寻找他了。
The city gate is closed.
城门已关闭。
I'm sure he's still in Bingzhou.
我确信他还在并州。
Listen.
听。
We have to capture Han Li before the Zhenxi Army.
我们必须 在镇西军之前擒获韩立。
See that.
看到那个。
(Which)
（哪个）
Guards!
卫兵！
Mr. Lv.
吕先生
Mr. Lv fainted suddenly.
吕先生突然晕倒了。
Alú escapes!
阿鲁逃脱！
Señor Shiqi.
Señor Shiqi.
This time I have brought many men.
这次我带了很多男人。
Where is Han Li?
韩立在哪里？
Have you caught it?
你抓到了吗？
I made a deal with the Cui family.
我和崔家做了一笔交易。
Whoever catches Han Li first will take over Bingzhou.
谁先抓住韩立，谁 就能占领并州。
Han Li fled as soon as the battle began.
战斗一开始，韩立就逃跑了。
But Bao chases after him.
但阿宝追赶他。
Let's go capture that cunning man.
我们去抓那个狡猾的人吧。
Chen Xing.
Chen Xing.
Lieutenant, Han Li is not in the car.
中尉， 韩立不在车上。
In fact it is clever.
事实上它很聪明。
Qiucui, don't worry.
秋翠，别担心。
Our servants
我们的仆人
They are on guard below.
他们在下面戒备。
Nobody can enter.
没有人可以进入。
Lady, they say
女士们，他们说
that the army will break into the city and sack it
军队将攻入这座城市 并洗劫它
and do all kinds of evil.
并作种种恶事。
Will our servants be able to stop them?
我们的仆人能阻止他们吗？
If they can stop them,
如果他们能阻止他们的话
We will be safe and healthy.
我们将会安全、健康。
If they don't stop them,
如果他们不阻止的话
What's the point of being afraid right now?
现在害怕有什么用呢？
This is the Third Lady's fault.
这都是三夫人的错。
If he does not curse you with the Master,
如果他不跟师父一起咒骂你，
You wouldn't have to volunteer to come.
你不必自愿来。
to Bingzhou for ancestor worship.
到并州 祭祖。
If it weren't for the Third Lady,
如果不是三夫人
we wouldn't be here in Bingzhou
我们不会在并州
(Prime Minister Gu's daughter,) and we wouldn't be in danger now.
（顾总理的女儿） 这样我们就不会有危险了。
(Gu Wan'niang) Qiucui, that's not true.
(顾万娘) 秋翠，这不是真的。
The third sister is right.
三姐说得对。
My father has six daughters.
我父亲有六个女儿。
I'm the only one who isn't smart
我是唯一一个不聪明的人
and has no rescue qualities.
并且不具备救援能力。
If I don't work harder,
如果我不更加努力的话
I will be even more useless.
我会更没用。
Third Lady was simply spouting nonsense.
三夫人 简直就是胡言乱语。
Don't take it personally.
别把它当成是针对你个人的。
Great Governor Sun wanted to appoint my father as prime minister.
孙大都欲任命 我父亲为相。
My father refused.
我父亲拒绝了。
Then, he was sent to jail.
然后，他被送进监狱。
All royal families in the capital city
首都的所有皇室家族
He admired him for his incorruptible integrity.
他钦佩 他的廉洁正直。
Now that he's finally free,
现在他终于自由了
You cannot leave the capital city.
你不能离开首都。
I am lucky to be able
我很幸运能够
travel to Bingzhou to pay tribute
前往并州悼念
to our ancestors in his name.
以他的名义向我们的祖先致敬。
If you are always like this,
如果你总是这样，
When can you live with your head held high?
什么时候才能 昂首挺胸地生活呢？
Even those servants in the residence
就连府邸里的那些仆人
They dare to treat you rudely now.
他们现在敢对你粗鲁了。
Don't worry, Master.
别担心，师父。
Persecutors have been fooled with that car.
迫害者被那辆车愚弄了。
Is there somewhere to hide here?
这里有什么地方可以藏身吗？
If you can seize someone's private residence
如果你可以夺取 某人的私人住宅
in broad daylight,
在光天化日之下，
Why don't you look to hide?
你为什么不找个 地方躲起来呢？
Mr. Han has always been a hero.
韩先生一直是英雄。
Miss.
错过。
But now, you are hiding in a lady's room.
但现在，你却躲在 女士的房间里。
Gives you no shame?
不给你丢脸吗？
Mr. Han.
何先生。
Don't you think you've fallen too low
你不觉得你已经堕落得太低了吗
If you have to keep a weak lady kidnapped?
如果你必须绑架一个弱女子？
You can't hit me.
你不能打我。
Since you are young master Cui study partner,
既然你是崔少的 学习伙伴，
Now that Bingzhou has fallen,
如今并州已陷，
the Zhenxi Army has more power.
镇西军势力更大。
Since you don't value Young Master Cui,
既然你不看重 崔公子，
Maybe you should join the Zhenxi Army instead.
也许你应该加入 镇西军。
You are already
你已经
in such a difficult situation.
在如此困难的情况下。
And yet, you're worried about my future.
然而， 你却担心我的未来。
I will never regret
我永远不会后悔
know you.
知道你。
And thanks
谢谢
for putting me in your good graces.
感谢您对我的青睐。
What's the point of putting you in my good graces?
让我对你好有什么意义？
Will you let me go?
你会让我走吗？
You have misunderstood me, Lord Han.
韩大人你误会了我的意思。
I can not thank you enough.
我不知道该怎么感谢你才足够。
Why would it bring you harm?
为什么会给你带来伤害？
Everyone in town says
镇上的每个人都说
that you are good at business.
你擅长做生意。
And that you are a rich man.
而且你是一个有钱人。
Now that I have been abandoned by the Cui family,
如今我已经 被崔家抛弃了，
I don't have anything.
我什么都没有
Please be understanding
请您理解
and give me a hand.
帮我一把。
Take them.
拿走这些。
These pieces of jewelry are very valuable.
这些珠宝 非常有价值。
take them
拿走这些
and join the Zhenxi Army.
并加入镇西军。
Miss!
错过！
Do not stay!
不要停留！
Miss.
错过。
If she comes here, I will kill her.
如果她来这里，我就会杀了她。
Miss!
错过！
Miss.
错过。
Miss, please forgive me.
小姐，请原谅我。
Thanks for saving my life.
谢谢你救了我的命。
Do not move!
不要动！
Lieutenant, should we fight them for him?
中尉， 我们应该为他而战吗？
I recognize defeat.
我承认失败。
I'm not anyone who can't admit defeat.
我不是一个 不能认输的人。
Are you okay, miss?
小姐，你还好吗？
Miss.
错过。
Hurry up.
赶快。
Come here.
过来。
Señor Shiqi.
Señor Shiqi.
Finally, we managed to capture this cunning man.
最终，我们成功 抓住了这个狡猾的人。
It's too late for the Cui Army.
崔军已经来不及了。
Now Han Li belongs to us.
现在韩立是我们的了。
Congratulations, Li Ni.
恭喜你，李妮。
Since you have managed to capture Han Li,
既然你擒获了韩立，
I will honor our deal.
我会履行我们的协议。
Bingzhou belongs to the Zhenxi Army now.
并州现属镇西军。
Gracias.
谢谢。
Han Li has been captured by the Zhenxi Army.
韩立已被 镇西军俘虏。
According to our deal, bingzhou belongs to them now.
按照我们的协议， 并州现在是他们的了。
That?
那？
When did they make that deal?
他们什么时候达成这笔交易的？
with the Zhenxi army?
与镇西军？
How will you be able to do it?
你将如何做到这一点？
Lieutenant, why didn't you tell me?
中尉， 你为什么不告诉我？
She already informed me about it beforehand.
她已经 提前告诉我这件事了。
She barely followed my order.
她几乎没有听从我的命令。
The Zhenxi Army is short on food.
镇西军缺粮。
Of
的
informed Young Master about it.
将此事通知了少爷。
As soon as we entered the city,
我们一进城，
We sent our men to clean up the food supplies.
我们派人去清理 食物供应。
Now, although the Zhenxi army has taken over Bingzhou,
现在，镇西军虽然 已经占领了并州，
They still don't have food.
他们还没有食物。
I see.
我懂了。
I would like to ask you please, Li.
我想请问一下你 ，李。
Are you finally going to let yourself help?
你终于要让 自己帮忙了吗？
We are Family.
我们是家人。
There is no need to be polite.
无需客气。
You are the commander of our army.
你是我们军队的指挥官。
Just give me your order.
只要给我你的订单。
Now that our army is in the city,
现在我军已进城，
We have to remain alert in case the Zhenxi Army
我们必须保持警惕 ，以防镇西军
He has an ulterior motive.
他别有用心。
I hope you can
我希望你可以
stationing a troop outside the city.
在城外驻扎军队。
If something happens in the city,
如果城里出了什么事
You can support us from outside.
您可以从外部支持我们。
Just in case.
万一。
Season...
季节...
Contribute a troop outside?
到外面派兵？
I'm sure you have a reason for this decision.
我相信你 做出这个决定是有原因的。
I will lead one troop and one station out of the city at a time.
我每次率一队一站出城。
Gracias.
谢谢。
We are Family.
我们是家人。
There is no need to be polite.
无需客气。
I know you don't like it.
我知道你不喜欢它。
That's why
这就是为什么
I sent him away from the city.
我送他离开这座城市。
Thank you, Young Master.
谢谢你，少爷。
No wonder Shu is nowhere to be found.
难怪舒找不到了。
You sent him outside the city early in the morning
你一早就送他出城了
to keep an eye on Cui Li.
监视崔莉。
You know me well, Ying.
你很了解我，英。
Have some tea.
喝点茶。
Let me pour it out for you.
让我给你倒出来。
Say it again if you dare.
如果你敢的话再说一遍。
GOOD.
好的。
Since you are slightly deaf, I will say it again.
既然你有点聋， 那我再说一遍。
The Cui Army
崔军
must deliver
必须交付
the foods you have eaten
你吃过的食物
and leave the city.
并离开城市。
The Zhenxi Army
The Zhenxi Army
He is magnanimous and kind.
他宽宏仁慈。
Since we are both
既然我们都是
They are fighting for the same throne,
他们为了同一个王位而战，
we will let you rest in Bingzhou
我们让你在并州休息
for one night before your departure.
出发前住一晚。
What do you think?
你怎么认为？
The Zhenxi army is generous enough, right?
镇西军 够大方了吧？
We are the ones who took down Bingzhou.
拿下并州的是我们。
The food supplies belong to the party that entered the city first.
粮食供应属于 先进城的一方。
Even though we made a deal with you,
尽管我们和你做了交易
now you have taken over Bingzhou.
现在你已经占领了并州。
Why do we have to give you food supplies?
为什么我们必须 给你们提供食物？
Do you think I'll be afraid of you
你觉得我会怕你吗
just because you slapped the table?
就因为你拍桌子了？
We went down Bingzhou together.
我们一起下并州。
Without the Zhenxi Army,
没有镇西军，
Han Li would have escaped to Jianzhou
韩立本来就逃到建州了
and tried to reclaim Bingzhou.
并试图收复并州。
How dare you say that.
你怎么敢这么说。
I said!
我说！
Give back our food supplies!
归还我们的粮食供应！
Say it again!
再说一遍！
Are you really deaf?
你真的聋了吗？
If we don't attack the city,
如果我们不攻城的话
you wouldn't have time to catch Han Li.
你根本就没有时间 去追韩立。
Return our food supplies
归还我们的食品供应
and get out of Bingzhou!
滚出并州！
Divina.
神曲。
Bro.
兄弟。
I'll kill you.
我会杀了你。
Han Li does not have the tiger bead.
韩立没有虎珠。
Keep searching.
不停寻找。
Roger that.
收到。
- That's complete nonsense. - Bright.
- 这完全是无稽之谈。 - 明亮的。
I'll kill you.
我会杀了你。
They are looking for
他们正在寻找
Han Li's residence completely.
韩立的住所彻底。
It seems that
看起来
the tiger account is not with Han Li.
虎帐不在韩立手上。
Young Master Cui there
崔少爷那里
has a fierce reputation on the battlefield.
在战场上有着凶猛的名声。
But now that I've seen it in person,
但现在我亲眼所见，
He is just a weak and weak man.
他只是一个软弱无力的人。
Never judge a book by its cover.
永远不要以封面来判断一本书。
He's just a cute boy.
他只是一个可爱的男孩。
How dare you say I didn't join the fight.
你怎么敢说 我没有参加战斗。
You were just a baby
你还只是个婴儿
when I was fighting in battle!
当我在战斗的时候！
We will fight if they dare!
如果他们敢，我们就战斗！
- Let's go then! - Come on!
- 那我们走吧！ - 快点！
I'm not a coward who's afraid of you.
我不是一个害怕你的胆小鬼。
Ven.
文。
I'm going to teach you a lesson,
我要给你一个教训
brother
兄弟
(Tang problem)
（唐问题）
Are you hungry?
你饿了吗？
I asked someone early in the morning.
我一 早就问过别人。
They are your favorites.
他们是你的最爱。
Thank you, Young Master.
谢谢你，少爷。
You are quite strong.
你很强。
It's delicious.
这很美味。
Where are you hitting?
你打哪里？
Yo...
哟...
Let me help you clean.
让我帮你打扫吧。
¡Detente!
缓和！
I'm hungry.
我饿了。
Let's eat first.
我们先吃饭吧。
¿Comer?
科默？
I'm not hungry.
我不饿。
I say I'm hungry.
我说我饿了。
Lieutenant.
中尉。
It seems that Li Ni found
看来李妮发现了
the pivot you have lost.
你失去的支点。
I never thought
我从来没想到
that Imperial grandfather,
那个皇太公，
the marshal of the Zhenxi Army,
镇西军元帅
I would be so greedy.
我会这么贪心。
He found your nail but refused to come back.
他找到了你的钉子 ，但拒绝回来。
And he even wears it openly in his head.
他甚至公开地把它戴在脑子里。
How shameless of him.
他多么无耻啊。
I'll go get it for you.
我去给你拿一下。
No.
不。
Don't make trouble.
别惹麻烦。
Look at the big picture.
看看大局。
I thought that the lieutenant
我还以为是中尉
lost its pivot.
失去了支点。
Why does Li Ni have it?
为什么李妮有呢？
Lieutenant He gave it to you.
中尉 他把它交给你了。
Qixi Lantern Festival
Qixi Lantern Festival
It has always been an important festival in Bingzhou.
历来是 并州的一个重要节日。
Now, we have two large armies in Bingzhou.
现在，我们并州有 两支大军。
Who do you think
你认为是谁
Will you accept our invitation?
您愿意接受我们的邀请吗？
I hope there is no fight.
我希望没有战斗。
Ask that pretty face of yours
问问你那张漂亮的脸
to go out.
出去。
Who is a pretty face?
谁是一张漂亮的脸？
The Zhenxi Army is the pretty face that wants a free ride.
镇西军是个 想搭顺风车的漂亮脸蛋。
Both armies fight a lot.
两军交战频繁。
A fight will eventually break out.
一场战斗最终会爆发。
If the city cannot be at peace,
如果这座城市不能安宁，
It is we who will be affected.
受影响的是我们。
I'm sorry for the wait.
抱歉让您久等了。
No need to apologize.
不用道歉。
According to our Young Master,
据我们少爷说，
Bingzhou has just begun to settle down.
并州刚刚开始 安定下来。
Everyone continues to live in fear.
每个人都继续生活在恐惧之中。
We need to hold a lively Lantern Festival celebration.
我们需要举办一场热闹的 元宵节庆祝活动。
Life can only go on
生活只能继续
when people feel safe.
当人们感到安全时。
And bring peace to the people
并给人民带来和平
That's why we fight for the throne.
这就是我们争夺王位的原因。
Everyone in the Cui army,
崔军众人，
including the Young Master, will attend the festival.
包括少爷在内， 都会参加这次祭典。
Please take care of us on that day
那天请多多关照
Of course.
当然。
It seems that
看起来
the Zhenxi army is not attending.
镇西军 不参加。
No, that's not true.
不，那不是真的。
Young Master Cui has said everything
崔少爷都说了
that my general transmits.
我的将军传达的信息。
The Zhenxi army will attend the festival as well.
镇西军 也将参加这个节日。
Gracias.
谢谢。
What's the point of having good hearing?
拥有良好的听力有什么意义？
You speak so slowly,
你说得那么慢，
Why are you here, Imperial Grandfather?
皇太公你怎么来了？
I need to ask the lieutenant something .
我有事要问中尉。
She's just a lieutenant.
她只是一名中尉。
If it concerns military matters,
如果是涉及军事问题的话
You can only talk to me about it.
你只能和我谈谈这件事。
It's a minor matter.
这是一件小事。
No need to bother you.
没必要打扰你。
I heard that Lieutenant He
听说何中尉
He was stranded in Han Li's residence a few days ago.
几天前他就被困在了韩立的住处。
And she only came out alive
而她只是活着出来
because I was under your care.
因为我在你的照顾下。
I should prepare a banquet
我应该准备一场宴会
to thank
感谢
for your help.
您的帮助。
The Cui Army is the main army fighting for the throne.
崔军是 争夺皇位的主力部队。
It is my duty.
这是我的职责。
You are too kind.
你太好了。
I grew up
我长大了
with Lieutenant Him since he was young.
从小就和贺中尉在一起。
We have a special relationship.
我们有着特殊的关系。
So, taking care of the lieutenant,
所以，照顾好中尉，
you have taken care of me too.
你也很照顾我。
I knew you would come.
我就知道你会来。
Why are you here, Young Master?
少爷你怎么来了？
I just want to visit you.
我只是想拜访你。
Greetings, Your Majesty.
您好，陛下。
You may be calm
你也许会平静
It was urgent today.
今天很紧急。
You're not hurt, are you?
你没有受伤吧？
Is a doctor needed?
需要医生吗？
Right now, General Pei Yuan
现在，裴渊将军
He has already sent a doctor to see me.
他已经派了医生 来给我看病。
Fortunately, I only have some minor cuts.
幸运的是，我只受了一些小伤口。
Nothing serious.
不严重。
I'm here to thank you.
我是来感谢你的。
If it weren't for you today,
如果今天没有你
I would have died.
我会死的。
There's no need.
没必要吧
It is not a big thing.
这不是什么大事。
Do not address me as Your Highness.
不要称呼我为殿下。
Call me with my title in the army.
请用我在军队中的头衔来称呼我。
Ven.
文。
The weather has turned cold.
天气变冷了。
And you're not dressed properly because of the cold.
而且你因为寒冷而没有穿好衣服。
No wonder you cough.
难怪你会咳嗽。
If Taozi discovers this,
如果桃子发现了这一点，
She will teach you again.
她会再教你。
I'm fine.
我很好。
Today, after keeping a close eye on Li Ni,
今天密切关注李妮之后，
In fact, he is an outstanding commander as you said.
事实上， 正如你所说，他是一位出色的指挥官。
We should never underestimate it.
我们永远不应该低估它。
Indeed, Li Ni is a wise strategist.
确实，李妮是一位睿智的战略家。
The Zhenxi Army is a formidable force.
镇西军是一支强大的力量。
If we can fight together,
如果我们能一起战斗
We can achieve victory with half the effort.
我们就能事半功倍地取得胜利。
But if we become enemies,
但如果我们成为敌人
to be honest,
说实话，
with an opponent like Li Ni,
面对李妮这样的对手，
I fear that
我担心
that we will not be able to defeat them.
我们将无法击败他们。
The Zhenxi Army is tied up fighting for the throne.
镇西军正忙于 争夺皇位。
It does not matter that,
没关系，
They will not become our enemies.
他们不会成为我们的敌人。
It's better to be safe than sorry.
安全总比后悔好。
Do you have any family in this city?
你在这个城市有家人吗？
I can ask Bao to send someone to take you home.
我可以叫阿宝派人送 你回家。
I haven't introduced myself yet.
我还没自我介绍呢。
My last name is Gu.
我姓顾。
Called Wan 'niang.
唤作万娘。
I am from the capital city.
我来自首都。
Last month, I came to Bingzhou
上个月，我来到并州
to pay tribute to my ancestors in the name of my father.
以我父亲的名义，向我的祖先致敬。
La familia Gu en Bingzhou.
La familia Gu en Bingzhou.
I remember that Prime Minister Gu
我记得顾总理
It belongs to the Gu family in Bingzhou as well.
也是并州顾氏的。
I heard that he called Sun Jing out for being a traitor in court.
听说他 在法庭上斥责孙敬是叛徒。
So, they sent him to jail.
于是，他们把他送进了监狱。
He is my father.
他是我的父亲。
In the end, to gain the support of the people,
最终，为了得到 人民的支持，
my father was released from prison
我父亲出狱了
and confined at home.
并被限制在家里。
So I traveled to Bingzhou to pay homage to our ancestors
于是我就去并州 祭拜祖先
and pray for my father.
并为我的父亲祈祷。
So, you are Prime Minister Gu's daughter.
这么说来，你是 顾总理的女儿。
Our country was overthrown
我们的国家被推翻了
and my father almost lost his life.
我的父亲差点丧命。
Fortunately, I ran into the Zhenxi army today.
幸好今天碰上了 镇西军。
And our army is really impressive
我们的军队确实令人印象深刻
y formidable.
y 太强大了。
I am willing to donate our family's food eaten in Bingzhou to the Zhenxi Army.
我愿意把我们家 在并州吃的粮食捐献给镇西军。
May victory be yours
愿胜利属于你
and claim the capital city soon.
并 很快占领首都。
That way, you can not only save people from this danger,
这样，你不仅可以 将人们从危险中拯救出来，
You can save my father too.
你也能救我父亲。
Prime Minister Gu is loyal
顾总理是忠诚的
and now, you are donating the food for our army.
现在，你们正在 为我们的军队捐赠粮食。
You are indeed the offspring of loyal family.
你们确实是忠贞家族的后代 。
I have a favor to ask.
我有件事想请你帮个忙。
I hope you can give me a hand.
我希望你能帮我一把。
Forward.
向前。
Now the nation is in chaos.
现在国家正处于混乱之中。
And Bingzhou is far from the capital city.
而并州距 京城较远。
I'm afraid I won't be able to return to the capital city alone.
我恐怕无法 独自回到京城了。
Please agree
请同意
let me travel with the army.
让我和军队一起旅行。
That way, I will be lucky enough to witness
这样我就有幸 见证
the claim of Xichang by the Zhenxi Army.
镇西军占领西昌。
It is not easy to march with the army.
随军行军并不容易。
It is not advisable to bring ladies with us.
不建议 带女士一起来。
No matter how difficult it is,
不管有多么困难，
I can accept it.
我可以接受。
If you are worried about us,
如果您担心我们，
Qiucui and I can dress like men.
我和秋翠可以穿得像个男人。
We won't cause you any problems.
我们不会给您带来任何问题。
It's better for me to send a team
我最好派一个团队
to accompany you back to the capital city.
陪你回京城。
You are busy with military matters.
你正忙于军事事务。
I don't want you to lower the size of your army to protect yourself.
我不希望你 为了保护自己而削减军队规模。
I just need to allow myself
我只需要允许自己
follow the army from behind.
从后面跟随军队。
Okay then.
好吧。
You can dress like a man
你可以穿得像个男人
and join the army.
并参军。
Thank you, General.
谢谢您，将军。
Stop there.
停在那里。
Detente.
缓和。
You widow without education.
你这个没有受过教育的寡妇。
Mrs. Shen. Teach them about proper etiquette.
沉太太。教他们 正确的礼仪。
Yes your Majesty.
是的，陛下。
The crown princess is from the inner court,
太子妃 是内廷出身，
in the front row.
前排。
Lady of the country is from the outer court,
国夫人 出自外廷，
in the first rank.
排名第一。
The crown princess has a higher rank.
太子妃的等级更高。
The lady of the country should greet the crown princess with a serene.
国夫人应该 以安详的姿态迎接太子妃。
That?
那？
Are you saying I should show my respect to her?
你是说我应该 尊重她吗？
Lady of Wei is the wife of the Great Governor.
卫夫人是大都督的夫人。
Great governor has achieved great merits.
伟大的统治者 立下了伟大的功业。
So, Your Highness
那么，殿下
has exempted you from having to greet her with a greeting.
免除了你向 她打招呼的麻烦。
I am the personal lady of His Highness.
我是殿下的贴身侍女。
I am in the sixth rank.
我排在第六位。
You are the servant of the lady of Wei.
你是魏国夫人的婢女。
You have no ranking.
你没有排名。
Which is it?
是哪一个？
A maid who has no ranking wants
没有等级的女仆想要
to hit a personal lady in the sixth rank?
打六品贴身小姐？
It sounds like you're confused about where you are.
听起来你 对自己所处的位置感到困惑。
You have no manners at all.
你根本就没有礼貌。
What a sharp tongue you have.
你的舌头多么锋利啊。
Thank you for the compliment, Madam de Wei.
谢谢德薇女士的夸奖。
The Great Governor is humble and courteous.
大督谦虚有礼。
Now that you have entered the palace,
既然已经进了皇宫，
you have to follow the rules and proper etiquette too
你也必须遵守规则 和适当的礼仪
so that you are not a laughing stock.
这样你就不会成为笑柄。
A laughable resource.
一个可笑的资源。
I want to see
我想看看
who dares to laugh at me now.
现在谁还敢笑我。
You will be taught a lesson if you have no manners.
如果你没有礼貌，就会受到教训。
You...
你...
You're crazy!
你疯了！
Stop crying.
别哭了。
To be honest,
说实话，
(Duke Zheng) rumors are quite unpleasant.
(郑公) 谣言甚不愉快。
Sin embargo, Xiao
罪禁运，萧
She is still the princess of the former crown.
她依然是前朝的王妃。
Since the former crown prince committed suicide,
自从前皇太子 自杀后，
I should have followed
我应该跟着
it made sense.
这是有道理的。
Even if he didn't,
即使他没有，
she should have become a nun to remain loyal to the former crown prince.
她应该成为一名修女，以保持 对前王储的忠诚。
great governor
伟大的州长
He is a wise man.
他是一个聪明人。
Because
因为
so he took this woman?
所以他就带走了这个女人？
She must have put a spell on him.
她一定是对他下了咒语。
Think about it.
想一想。
With the years,
随着岁月的流逝，
Had married
已经结婚了
so many wives and concubines.
妻妾如此之多。
But he had never hated anyone before.
但他从来没有恨过任何人。
I can't allow this to continue.
我不能允许这种情况继续下去。
Don't panic.
不要恐慌。
There are still countless battles ahead of us.
我们面前还有无数的战斗。
The Great Governor still needs the Chenjun Yuan Clan
大督还需要 陈君元氏
fight for him and call him food.
为他而战 并称他为食物。
He won't treat us badly.
他不会亏待我们的。
But this Xiao
但这萧
He is adamant about staying in the palace.
他坚决要留在皇宫。
Maybe
或许
He has an ulterior motive.
他别有用心。
We'll find out what it is eventually.
我们最终会知道它是什么。
So,
所以，
I will discuss this with our relatives
我会和我们的亲戚讨论这个问题
and convince the Great Governor to kill this woman
并说服大总督 杀死这个女人
for what he did to you.
因为他对你所做的事。
You can go.
你可以走了。
The river appears clear and shallow.
河水显得清澈又浅。
But how far apart are the river banks?
但河岸相距多远？
The Qixi Festival will be here soon.
七夕节马上就要到了。
we saw each other for the first time
我们第一次见面
en la noche de Qixi.
en la noche de Qixi.
If I had known this would happen,
如果我早知道会发生这样的事
We should never have known him.
我们根本不应该认识他。
Why are you saying something so negative again?
怎么又说 这么消极的话了？
Are you crazy yet
你疯了吗
Still crazy about Lady de Wei?
还迷恋德薇夫人吗？
I have lived in the palace for a long time.
我在皇宫里住了很长时间了。
This kind of thing happens often.
这种事情经常发生。
It's normal for others
对别人来说很正常
favor the one who has power.
偏爱有权力的人。
Once you lose power, they will take a step for you.
一旦你失去权力， 他们就会为你采取行动。
Hoy,
嘿，
Madam Wei slapped my personal lady.
魏夫人打了我的贴身小姐一巴掌。
If I didn't retaliate,
如果我不反击的话
one day,
一天，
I would kill myself with poison.
我会用毒药自杀。
Do you think that
你认为
will punish his legal wife
将惩罚他的合法妻子
for me?
为我？
I do not think it does.
我认为不会。
El Clan Yuan de Chenjun
El Clan Yuan de Chenjun
It's your wife's clan.
这是你妻子的家族。
And you have always trusted them.
而你一直信任他们。
I have offended Madam Wei today.
今天我得罪了魏夫人。
She should leave the palace and become a nun.
她应该离开皇宫 ，成为一名修女。
In that way,
以这种方式，
I won't be a thorn in someone's flesh.
我不会成为别人的肉中刺。
You're trying to hit me.
你想打我。
I would not dare.
我不敢。
I'm just afraid that if I stay here,
我只是担心 如果我留在这里
I will die one day without knowing what killed me.
有一天我会死去，却不知道 是什么杀死了我。
I better become a nun
我最好成为一名修女
and stay away from all curses.
并远离一切咒诅。
I want to see
我想看看
what monastery
什么修道院
can handle you.
可以对付你。
You can build a monastery for me.
你可以为我建造一座修道院。
In a quiet and beautiful place.
在一个安静而美丽的地方。
I want him to be close to Xichang.
我想让他靠近西昌。
That way, it will be easy to visit me.
这样的话， 来拜访我就很容易了。
But maybe after leaving the palace,
但也许离开皇宫后
you will forget everything about me
你会忘记我的一切
In a few days.
在几天内。
Do you really want to be a nun?
你真的想当尼姑吗？
I don't want to stay in the palace anymore.
我不想再呆在皇宫里了。
Lady of Wei
卫国夫人
He is not a magnanimous person.
他不是一个宽宏大量的人。
She likes to make things difficult for me.
她喜欢为难 我。
Furthermore, everyone in the palace
而且，宫里的所有人
He has a sharp tongue.
他的舌头很尖。
I don't want to
我不想
be gossiped about by them already.
已经被他们八卦了。
Forget about being nuns.
忘记当修女吧。
But
但
your personal lady, Mrs. Shen,
您的贴身女士沉太太，
He seems like someone with a lot of fortune.
他看起来像是一个拥有很多财富的人。
Maybe she can become a nun instead of you.
也许她可以 代替你成为一名修女。
Finally, you have told the truth.
终于，你说了实话。
To preserve the dignity of the Lady of Wei,
为了维护卫国夫人的尊严，
do you want to send my maid
你想派我的女仆吗
to become a nun.
成为一名修女。
Just give me a glass of poisoned liquor.
给我 一杯毒酒就行了。
Mrs. Shen and me
我和沉太太
will drink that poisoned liquor at once.
立刻喝掉那杯毒酒。
She is your maid.
她是你的女仆。
She offended Madam Wei.
她得罪了魏夫人。
I have no choice but to punish her.
我别无选择，只能惩罚她。
And the Lady of Wei's servant?
还有卫国夫人的婢女？
I offended me.
我冒犯了我。
You'll
你会
ask her to become a nun too?
要求她也出家为尼？
Look to you.
看你。
Are
是
so eager to win at everything.
如此渴望赢得一切。
If you act justly and punish that servant too,
如果你行事公正， 也惩罚那个仆人，
I will send Mrs. Shen away to become a nun.
我将送沉夫人出家 为尼。
Otherwise, it's not an opportunity.
不然的话，就不是机会了。
Are you pinching your tunic?
你在捏你的外衣吗？
Let me help you.
我来帮你。
Forget it.
忘了它。
I'm better at this than you.
我比你更擅长这一点。
When you pack up your torn tights last time,
当你上次收起撕破的裤袜时
those points were as long as centipedes.
这些点 有蜈蚣那么长。
I want to ask you something.
我想问你点事儿。
Listen
听
you're going to let Miss Gu
你要让顾小姐
You travel with our army in men's clothing, right?
你是穿着男装随我军出行的吧？
Yeah.
是的。
She's alone
她独自一人
with his maid.
和他的女仆。
He wants to return to the capital city.
他要回 京城。
It is a battlefield everywhere.
到处都是战场。
She can't survive the trip alone.
她无法独自度过这次旅行。
Instead,
反而，
can travel together with our army.
可以和我们的军队一起旅行。
This is the first time.
这是第一次。
This is the first time I see you treating a lady so kindly.
我还是第一次见你 对一个女士如此友善。
Are you going to become
你会成为
a resplendent old woman when there is no war?
没有战争的时候是一位光彩照人的老妇人？
No.
不。
I really think that
我真的认为
that Miss Gu is a good woman.
说顾小姐是个好女人。
It's good enough for you.
这对你来说已经足够好了。
It's good for you.
这是对你有好处。
It seems that you have fallen in with Miss Gu.
看来你已经和顾小姐有缘了。
¿Yo?
¿哟？
This is easy.
这很容易。
I am going to write a letter to Great General Pei
我要给裴大将军写信
to propose to you.
向你求婚。
No.
不。
What nonsense are you talking about?
你在说什么废话？
You're the one he likes.
你是他喜欢的人。
For the first time,
首次，
you allowed a woman
你允许一个女人
travel with our army.
与我们的军队一起旅行。
So stop dragging me into this.
所以别再把我拖进去了。
What about being a woman?
身为女人又怎样呢？
Look at Lieutenant He of the Cui family.
再看看 崔家的何副将。
She is smart and cunning.
她聪明又狡猾。
And she's good at leading her troops.
而且她善于带兵。
He's so much better than so many men out there.
他比外面的很多男人都要优秀得多。
From what you have said,
从你所说的来看，
It seems that you are in love with the lieutenant
看来 你爱上了中尉
instead of Miss Gu.
而不是顾小姐。
Without sense.
毫无意义。
Has no sense?
有没有意义？
Lieutenant.
中尉。
The paper mill.
造纸厂。
I recovered the paper mill you left at the inn.
我收回了你留在旅馆的造纸厂。
Show me.
给我看看。
But wait.
可是等等。
This is just a paper mill.
这只是一个造纸厂。
Why did you leave it on the counter at the inn ?
你为什么把它留 在旅馆的柜台上？
if you were going to send me to look for him?
如果你要 派我去找他吗？
Mira.
米拉.
This is just a toy
这只是一个玩具
that is sold in a market.
在市场上出售的。
It is not unique and has no value.
它不是唯一的，也没有价值。
And it has broken.
它已经坏了。
Why do you keep it?
你为什么保留它？
It's broken?
坏了？
Mira.
米拉.
It wasn't broken
它没有坏掉
when I gave it to the innkeeper.
当我把它交给旅店老板时。
It seems that
看起来
He didn't take good care of him.
他没有好好照顾他。
It's broken here too.
这里也坏了。
This is not how you fix it.
这不是解决问题的方法。
You will be cut by the bamboo strip.
你会被竹条割伤。
Let me do it.
让我来做吧。
This type of work is not for you.
这种类型的工作不适合你。
It's fixed.
它是固定的。
Let's attend the Lantern Festival tomorrow night together.
明天晚上我们一起去参加元宵节吧。
Don't you have to direct the program tomorrow?
明天你不用 导演节目吗？
I already named someone else
我已经指定了其他人
to do that kind of boring task.
去做那种无聊的任务。
And you?
你呢？
Do you have to accompany you , Young Master Cui?
崔少爷要陪你吗？
No.
不。
It's a deal then.
那么就达成协议了。
See you then.
回头见。
Lieutenant.
中尉。
Did you fix the windmill?
你修好风车了吗？
Yeah.
是的。
Lieutenant.
中尉。
Let's enjoy the Lantern Festival together at night.
晚上我们一起赏元宵吧。
I have things to do tonight.
今晚我还有事要做。
I'll pass.
我会通过。
Are you going to accompany
你要陪吗
Young Master to the Lantern Festival?
少爷来元宵节？
Sitting under the well-lit shed
坐在光线充足的棚子下
Why do people gossip?
人们为什么会八卦？
I'll pass.
我会通过。
What do you have to do then?
那你该怎么办？
Yo,
哟，
I am afraid that the Zhenxi army
恐怕镇西军
I will do something secretly.
我会秘密做一些事情。
So I have to keep an eye on them
所以我必须留意他们
to find out what your plan is.
了解您的计划是什么。
Alright. I will go with you
好吧。我会和你一起去
to help you.
来帮你。
You do not have to do it.
您不必这样做。
You can keep an eye on Xie Chang'er of the Zhenxi Army for me.
你替我留意一下 镇西军的谢嫦儿。
It's not just him
不只是他
the man Li Ni trusts,
李妮信任的男人，
can gather intelligence from the sound of the wind.
可以从风声中收集情报。
You have to watch him closely.
你必须仔细观察他。
Don't give him any chance to act secretly.
不给他任何 秘密行动的机会。
Ear.
耳朵。
Why are you pulling such a long face?
你为什么拉这么长的脸？
Mr. Shiqi has ordered us to behead Han Li in public.
十七先生命令我们 当众斩杀韩立。
during the Lantern Festival
元宵节期间
to make a name for the Zhenxi Army.
为镇西军扬名。
Yeah.
是的。
We have done everything
我们已经做了一切
according to Mr. Shiqi's order.
按照世奇先生的吩咐。
but he asked me
但他问我
to drive away Miss Taozi
赶走桃子小姐
of the lieutenant.
中尉的。
Because?
因为？
Since someone
既然有人
Taozi does not want to follow Lieutenant He,
桃子不愿意 跟着何中尉，
It means that another person in your place wants to follow you.
这意味着有另一个人 在你的位置上想要跟随你。
Just do what he said.
按他说的做就行了。
But how can I
但我怎样才能
Lure Miss Taozi out?
把桃子小姐引出来？
Do they knock her out?
他们会把她击倒吗？
She uses poison and is cunning.
她使用毒药，而且很狡猾。
If he had to fight her, he couldn't win.
如果他必须和她战斗， 他赢不了。
Your brain
你的脑
It is made of wood.
它是由木头制成的。
You can just invite her
你可以邀请她
to enjoy
享受
the Lantern Festival with you.
与你共度元宵节。
Here you have.
在这里你有。
Think about it.
想一想。
Miss Taozi.
Miss Taozi.
What if we enjoy
如果我们享受怎么办
the Lantern Festival together today?
今天一起过元宵节吗？
Why do you invite me?
你为什么邀请我？
Because I'm alone today.
因为今天我一个人。
Others have other things to do.
其他人还有其他事情要做。
And it seems that
而且似乎
you are alone too.
你也孤独一人。
And we
和我们
so you are inviting me
所以你邀请我
because you are bored.
因为你很无聊。
No.
不。
No, Miss Taozi.
不，桃子小姐。
That's not what I was referring to.
我指的不是这个。
Forget it.
忘了它。
Forget what I said.
忘了我说的话。
Stop there.
停在那里。
Since you wanted to invite me,
既然你想邀请我，
then you invite me.
那你邀请我。
Why are you changing your mind now?
你为什么现在改变主意了？
Who do you think I am?
你觉得我是谁？
No. Miss Taozi.
不是，桃子小姐。
- Let me explain. - I'm with you.
- 让我解释。 - 我和你在一起。
Enjoy the Lantern Festival together.
一起过 元宵节。
Thank you, Miss Taozi.
谢谢桃子小姐。
No need to thank me.
不用谢我。
After all, you have saved me from trouble.
毕竟，你救了我脱离困境。
What a problem?
有什么问题吗？
Come take a look.
快来看看吧。
Be careful.
当心。
Why are you dressing like that today?
你今天为什么穿成这样？
You look beautiful.
你看起来很美。
Since I'm here to spy on someone,
既然我是来监视某人的
Of course I need to change.
我当然需要改变。
This is a trick
这是一个技巧
make others let their guard down.
让别人放松警惕。
Indeed, you are wise.
确实，你很聪明。
Let's get down to business.
我们开始谈正事吧。
You are so pretty today.
你今天真漂亮。
I almost couldn't recognize you.
我差点认不出你了。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
Amazing!
惊人的！
Again!
再次！
Incredible!
极好的！
That's great!
那太棒了！
Windmills,
风车，
beautiful and fun windmills.
美丽又有趣的风车。
Again!
再次！
Genial.
和蔼可亲。
Give me a windmill, please.
请给我一个风车。
Choose one.
选一个。
I take this.
我接受这个。
Alright.
好吧。
Pay for it.
付钱。
Do you like windmills?
你喜欢风车吗？
Not really.
并不真地。
But our lieutenant has a windmill
但我们的中尉有一个风车
in his notebook.
在他的笔记本上。
GOOD!
好的！
And he is always in a good mood
而且他总是心情很好
when you see him every day.
当你每天看到他的时候。
He refused to throw it away.
他拒绝扔掉它。
when it broke out that day.
那天爆发的时候。
She even fixed herself.
她连自己都修好了。
But paper mills are not expensive.
但造纸厂并不昂贵。
Only two copper coins.
只有两枚铜币。
It's true.
这是真的。
I told him the same.
我也这么告诉他。
I told him we could buy a new one together.
我告诉他我们可以 一起买一件新的。
But she said she wouldn't understand.
但她说她听不懂。
She said
她说
than to buy a windmill yourself
还不如自己买个风车
It wasn't as fun as getting a windmill as a gift.
这并不像收到 风车作为礼物那么有趣。
So when I just saw that person,
所以当我刚看到那个人的时候
I told myself
我告诉自己
that I wanted someone
我想要某人
to give me one too.
也给我一份。
I want to see
我想看看
how fun a windmill can be
风车有多有趣
when it is a gift from someone else.
当它是别人的礼物时。
Is that why you asked me to buy it for you?
这就是 你让我给你买的原因吗？
I'm sure you feel honored
我相信你会感到荣幸
to buy something for myself.
给自己买东西。
Yes Yes.
是的是的。
But what's so fun
但有什么好玩的
to get a windmill as a gift?
得到风车作为礼物？
Why don't I feel the same?
为什么我没有同样的感觉？
Am I dreaming or is the river full of stars?
是我在做梦 ，还是河里布满了星星？
This place is beautiful.
这个地方很漂亮。
The stars at Laolan Pass
老兰关的星星
They are much bigger
它们更大
and closer.
更近了。
When you're lying in the desert at midnight,
当你半夜躺在沙漠里时，
The sky is as dark as silk.
天空漆黑如丝。
Like you could touch the star
就像你可以触摸星星
just extending it.
只是扩展它。
We have steppe
我们有草原
as far as the eyes can see in Pingliang.
平凉一望无际。
When he was young,
当他年轻的时候，
My father went hunting with me.
我父亲和我一起去打猎。
Sometimes, I would fall asleep on the back of the horse.
有时，我会在马背上睡着。
When I woke up and opened my eyes,
当我醒来睁开眼睛时，
I could see every star
我可以看到每一颗星星
in the sky.
在天上。
They looked like sugar crystals that were about to fall.
它们看起来就像 即将掉落的糖晶体。
I grew up in the capital.
我在首都长大。
After learning to walk,
学会走路后，
always rides alone to go
总是一个人骑车去
al Wonderland.
阿尔仙境。
The Wonderland is a famous place in the capital city.
仙境是 京城的著名景点。
It is located on high ground.
它位于高地。
On,
在，
you can overlook the entire capital city.
可以俯瞰整个首都。
Hear the fox and the chirp in the forest, see the rainbow on the other side.
听到森林里狐狸的叫声， 看到彼岸的彩虹。
Feel the west breeze in the wonders.
在奇观中感受西风。
Keep riding deep into the sunset.
继续骑行到日落深处。
May the sun never set.
愿太阳永不落山。
So, you like this poem.
那么，你喜欢这首诗。
But I like the other one.
但我喜欢另一张。
Wait.
等待。
I know which one you like.
我知道你喜欢哪一个。
That?
那？
There is grass everywhere on the prairie.
草原上到处都是青草。
Each year, it will wither during the fall.
每年秋天，它都会枯萎。
But you can never burn it.
但你永远不能烧掉它。
Will be back again when spring is here.
春天来的时候会再次回来。
Is that the only one?
这是唯一的一个吗？
How do you know I like that poem?
你怎么知道 我喜欢那首诗？
Know your enemies well so you can defeat them.
充分了解你的敌人， 这样你才能击败他们。
See
看
that Li Ni is someone like that.
李妮就是这样的人。
That's why I know
这就是为什么我知道
that you like this poem.
你喜欢这首诗。
You're amazing, Lieutenant.
你太棒了，中尉。
You are my close friend.
你是我亲密的朋友。
I like that.
我喜欢。
Without sense.
毫无意义。
I did not say
我没说过
I am your bosom friend.
我是你的知心朋友。
that you said that
你这么说
Why is my dress wet?
为什么我的衣服湿了？
This is bad. The boat is leaking.
这不好。船漏水了。
♪ If I forget the waste of time ♪
♪ 如果我忘记浪费时间 ♪
♪ Wait for the memories ♪
♪ 等待回忆 ♪
♪ smash and sink ♪
♪ 粉碎并沉没 ♪
♪ The emotional scars on your heart ♪
♪ 你心中的情感伤痕 ♪
♪ They are the mess ♪
♪ 他们真是一团糟 ♪
♪ I find it difficult to let go ♪
♪ 我发现很难放手 ♪
♪ If the longing is not forgotten ♪
♪ 如果没有忘记渴望 ♪
♪ I long to return to the first moment ♪
♪ 渴望回到 最初的时刻 ♪
♪ The affection we had in our fateful situation ♪
♪ 我们在命运的处境中所拥有的感情♪
♪ How I wish to keep it for you ♪
♪ 我多么想为你保留它 ♪
♪ If you still remember love ♪
♪ 如果你还记得爱情 ♪
♪ The promises we made ♪
♪ 我们许下的承诺 ♪
♪ Even if this love hurts me ♪
♪ 即使这份爱让我受伤 ♪
♪ I will continue living for you ♪
♪ 我会继续为你而活 ♪
♪ holding on to memories ♪
♪ 紧紧抓住回忆 ♪
♪ Wait it's my persistence ♪
♪ 等等，这是我的坚持 ♪
♪ If love remembers ♪
♪ 如果爱还记得 ♪
♪ The promise I made to you ♪
♪ 我对你的承诺 ♪
♪ Despite going against destiny ♪
♪ 尽管违背命运 ♪
♪ I don't regret loving you ♪
♪ 我不后悔爱你 ♪
♪ I am willing to sacrifice you ♪
♪ 我愿意牺牲你 ♪
♪ While waiting for your response ♪
♪ 在等待您的回复时 ♪
♪ If love is remembered ♪
♪ 如果爱还记得 ♪
♪ The promise I made to you ♪
♪ 我对你的承诺 ♪
♪ Despite going against destiny ♪
♪ 尽管违背命运 ♪
♪ I don't regret loving you ♪
♪ 我不后悔爱你 ♪
♪ I am willing to sacrifice you ♪
♪ 我愿意牺牲你 ♪
♪ While I wait for your response ♪
♪ 在等待你的回复时 ♪